

ABOUT ME

Working in collaboration with product managers, developers, executives, and design teams I help make products into solutions that fulfill user needs. Users needs are found through thoughtful user research and testing efforts, market research, and understanding business goals. These are then translated into simple user personas and user journey maps that help us gain a deeper understanding of and empathy for our users. Then we can produce the proper wireframes, components, sitemaps, interaction patterns and prototypes that help fill user needs in intuitive ways. Iterating and reevaluating then helps to find and close user gaps and streamline the workflows of our users.

By implementing prescriptive levels of UX process it allows us to range from the simplest of iterative processes to more complex processes to meet user needs regardless of the size of the feature or project. This is especially helpful in smaller organizations and organizations that haven't had a strong UX presence. As the advocate for the user I find ways to combine the users needs and the business goals so both are accomplished. Testing design prototypes with users rather than developed software significantly cuts time spent redeveloping features that missed the mark.

Bringing the cross organizational teams together to collaborate on the products builds trust. That trust builds speed helps to ensure we deliver features that meet user needs and requirements and fills user gaps in a timely manner. Uniting these teams crates a feeling of ownership and empathy for our users and the problems they may encounter. This cross collaboration also generates more ideas from a more diverse group and can lead to unexpected insights and innovations.

Retaining the integrity of the product can be a difficult task. By implementing living component and pattern libraries that are accessible to everyone enables us to flex with user needs and business goals. This method facilitates UX at scale by democratization allowing us to build consistent and replicable experiences for our users. We can then more quickly and easily iterate because we are all speaking the same design language.

CONTACT

801.726.4617

steven@stevenjeppesen.com

in linkedin.com/in/stevenjeppesen

EDUCATION

2011 Utah State University

Bachelors of Fine Art Graphic Design

Associates German Language

Cooper

Interaction Design Workshop



EXPERIENCE

2018

Overstock.com | Senior UX Product Designer | April 2018 - Present | \$\&\circ\$ 801.947.3100

- Lead the User Experience, UX Vision and strategy for Overstocks enterprise software that allows overstocks partners to get products onto the retail website.
- Ran a design inventory and implemented a component & pattern library to bring a new level of consistency.
- Ran a platform inventory to evaluate sitemap efficiency.
- Run user testing both in person and remotely.

2016

- Work with product managers, engineer teams, leadership, and other key stake holders to meet both business and user needs.
- Design and create fully-interactive prototypes & click-throughs to better communicate user stories to executives, engineers, and users.

NICE inContact | Sr. Interaction Designer | August 2015 – April 2018 | \$801.320.3200

- Lead the interaction and visual design for multiple SaaS based applications.
- Create new experiences that answer market problems and make our software a market leader.
- · Run user testing both in person and remotely.
- Work alongside product managers & engineer teams to meet both business and user needs.
- Assist in producing style guides and interaction specification sheets for engineers.
- Design and create fully-interactive prototypes & click-throughs to better communicate user stories to executives, engineers, and users.

2012

2015

FranklinCovey | UX Designer | March 2012 - August 2015 | \$801.817.1776

- Design and direct the UX of multiple sites, apps, and marketing micro-sites in a team environment.
- Use user stories and other data to create compelling navigation and page layout in both native and responsive web environments.
- Created a new fully responsive template system for marketing emails. This helped the marketing department be faster to market and more agile.
- Code full websites, micro-sites and marketing emails using best practices and standards.